Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/animaanandkumar (LinkedIn) users.cms.caltech.edu/~anima (Personal) aws.amazon.com/machinelearning/ (Company)

Top Skills
Data Mining
Python
Signal Processing

Anima Anandkumar

Director of ML research at NVIDIA and Bren Professor at Caltech San Francisco Bay Area

Summary

Animashree (Anima) Anandkumar is a Bren professor at Caltech CMS department and a director of machine learning research at NVIDIA. Her research spans both theoretical and practical aspects of large-scale machine learning. In particular, she has spearheaded research in unsupervised AI, deep learning, optimization and tensor methods. Previously, she was a principal scientist at Amazon Web Service, where she has enabled machine learning on the cloud infrastructure.

Anima is the recipient of several awards and honors such as the Bren named chair professorship at Caltech, Alfred. P. Sloan Fellowship, Young investigator awards from the Air Force and Army research offices, Faculty fellowships from Microsoft, Google, Facebook, and Adobe, and several best paper awards. She was recently nominated to the World Economic Forum's Expert Network consisting of leading experts from academia, business, government, and the media. She has been featured in documentaries by PBS, KPCC, wired magazine, and in articles by MIT Technology review, Forbes, Yourstory, O'Reilly media, and so on. At Caltech, she is the co-director of the center for Decision Making, Optimization and Learning (DOLCIT) and is on the scientific advisory committee for the Center for Autonomous Systems and Technologies (CAST). Anima has worked to democratize AI, promote ethical use and improve diversity and inclusion in Al. She was awarded the good tech award 2018 by NYTimes for her efforts.

Experience

NVIDIA
Director of ML research
September 2018 - Present (2 years)
San Francisco Bay Area

I recently joined NVIDIA as director of ML research. I am hiring ML researchers and engineers at all levels as well as graduate student interns.

NORC at the University of Chicago Member Of The Board Of Advisors October 2019 - Present (11 months)

Greater Chicago Area

Caltech

Bren Professor

June 2017 - Present (3 years 3 months)

I am a Bren Professor and co-director of DOLCIT in the department of computing + mathematical sciences (CMS).

Amazon Web Services
Principal Scientist
October 2016 - August 2018 (1 year 11 months)
Palo Alto, California

I am a principal scientist at Amazon AI working on a range of large-scale machine learning solutions on AWS cloud. This includes SageMaker platform for machine learning, the Apache Mxnet deep learning framework, and AI services such as Rekognition for computer vision, Lex & Comprehend for NLP etc. https://aws.amazon.com/amazon-ai/

UC Irvine
Associate professor
August 2016 - June 2017 (11 months)

University of California Irvine Assistant Professor 2010 - 2016 (6 years)

MIT

Postdoctoral researcher July 2009 - July 2010 (1 year 1 month)

I am a postdoctoral researcher with Alan Willsky at the Laboratory of Information and Decision Systems.

Cornell University
Phd Student
August 2004 - August 2009 (5 years 1 month)
Detection and estimation in sensor networks

IBM

Graduate Research Intern 2008 - July 2008 (less than a year)

IBM T. J. Watson Research Graduate Research Intern June 2007 - September 2007 (4 months)

Student Research Intern: worked on real-time monitoring in model-based transaction systems, proposed solutions based on matching algorithms and derived performance guarantees.

Education

Cornell University

Phd, Electrical Engineering (2004 - 2009)

Indian Institute of Technology, Madras
B. Tech, Electrical Engineering (2000 - 2004)

Indian Institute of Science (IISc)